# José Manuel Salazar Pérez

Full Stack Developer - IT Engineer

- México City | 📧 jose salazar @outlook.com | 📱 777-780-0411
- [LinkedIn] (https://www.linkedin.com/in/jos%C3%A9-salazar-a67980a9/)
- [GitHub] (<a href="https://github.com/josemsp">https://github.com/josemsp</a>)
- [Portfolio] (https://josemsp.github.io/my-portfolio/)

## **Professional Profile**

Software developer with over 7 years of experience in web applications. Specialized:

- JavaScript | React | Node.js
- SQL/NoSQL databases
- Serverless architectures

My goal is to provide innovative solutions that improve efficiency and user experience, while continuing to develop my skills.

## Work Experience

### \*\*Andonix\*\* | Full Stack Developer

\*Sep 2019 - Jul 2024\*

- \*\*Key Achievements:\*\*
- Backend optimization: Refactoring of lambdas, improving performance and scalability.
- **Frontend Development:** Implementation of reusable React components, reducing development time by 30% and initial loading time by 25%.
- **Data Integration:** Refactoring of functions for data replication in Power BI and Google Looker Studio, enhancing data analysis flow.

#### \*\*Sección Amarilla\*\* | Full Stack Developer

\*Jul 2017 - Sep 2019\*

- \*\*Key Achievements:\*\*
- **My Negocio:** As the lead developer, I updated and improved processes for this platform and ensured the delivery of new features with high quality and within established deadlines.
- **Frontend Development:** Creation of a "Do it yourself" project for Sección Amarilla users to create their own websites.
- Openpay: Creation of payment process with Openpay platform.

### \*\*Grupo Salinas\*\* | Backend Developer

\*Feb 2016 - May 2017\*

\*\*Responsibilities:\*\*

- **Backend:** Maintenance, updating, processing, and improvement of data flow for the information collection system and business portfolio of Grupo Salinas.

### **Technical Skills**

Frontend	Backend	BD	DevOps & Tools
		-	-
React.js	Node.js	MongoDB	Git
JavaScript	Lambda	SQL	SCRUM
HTML/CSS	Express	Mongoose	CI/CD
Typescript			

## Education

\*\*Bachelor of Information and Communication Technologies\*\* Universidad Tecnológica de la Huasteca Hidalguense | 2015

# Languages

- 🔀 Spanish: Native

- English: Intermediate